<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/styles/feed.css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>My Geekdom</title>
<atom:link href="http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed</link>
<description>Ramblings about my nerdy pursuits</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-02-03T23:32:34-05:00</dc:date>
<admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="http://nanoblogger.sourceforge.net" />
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/02/03/this_blog_is_now_hosted_for_free_and_its_slashdot_proof_too/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/02/03/this_blog_is_now_hosted_for_free_and_its_slashdot_proof_too/index.html</guid>
<title>This Blog Is Now Hosted For Free (and it's slashdot proof too)</title>
<dc:date>2012-02-03T21:49:09-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>blog</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<!-- NANOBLOGGER METADATA - END -->

<!-- The posting body follows this END_HTML directive -->

<p>
While there are many free or nearly free blog hosting sites available, most of them come with a long list of restrictions. Either they restrict you to using their blogging software, throw ads on your pages, give you the "unlimited bandwidth" plan that they'll cut off if your site gets too much traffic, limit you to only the ugly themes, etc&hellip; 
</p>
<p>
But <a href="http://neilsmithline.com">neilsmithline.com</a> is now hosted on a site that charges me nothing, doesn't put ads on my pages, couldn't care less about the theme I use, and, should I ever be lucky enough, survive <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slashdotting">slashdotting</a>. The only restriction is that my blog has to be static. Being that I already had a static blog (see <a href="#about-this-blogs-tech.org">previous posting</a>), this was no problem for me at all. I've used lots of dynamic blogs (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drupal">Drupal</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordpress">WordPress</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joomla">Joomla</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blogger_(service)">Blogger</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Movable_Type">Movable Type</a>, etc&hellip;) and just found that "dynamic" is a short way of saying that the blogging system is going to do what it wants and not what I want.
</p>
<p>
Along with the free hosting I get automatic version control, well-managed collaboration (not that I have any collaborators), data redundancy, eternal archiving (I probably won't need it that long but it's nice to know that nothing will get lost), and the ability to get a copy of my data onto my local machine whenever I want it.
</p>
<p>
My choice of blogging technology was largely influenced by these two blog postings, <a href="http://decafbad.com/blog/2011/06/08/further-jekyll-notes">1</a> and <a href="http://decafbad.com/blog/2011/06/08/moved-to-jekyll">2</a>, and email conversations I had with their author, <a href="https://plus.google.com/114487965928288927815/about">Les Orchard</a>. While Les went with <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>, I preferred the simpler <a href="http://nanoblogger.sourceforge.net/">NanoBlogger</a>. Les uses <a href="http://github.com">Github.com</a> for versioning his blog but hosts his blog on his own site as he wants full control of what is published. I simply couldn't agree with him more. 
</p>
<p>
When I moved to my new blogging framework, I quickly got my blog up and running using NanoBlogger for site generation and sftp to publish it to my VPS. Today I investigated replacing sftp with Github and its notification framework. This would essentially mirror Les's blog system except that I am running NanoBlogger locally while he runs Jekyll. 
</p>
<p>
As I was investigating using Github for transportation and archiving of my blog, I decided to take another look at <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a>. And then, like a lightning bolt, it occurred to me. When I publish my blog by pushing it to Github, if the repository has the magic name of <i>neil-smithline.github.com</i>, then Github would publish my blog at <a href="http://neil-smithline.github.com/">http://neil-smithline.github.com/</a> automatically. There simply was no benefit to serve my blog from my VPS as Github would do it far better than I could on my VPS.
</p>
<p>
The only problem I foresee is that I run more than just my blog on <a href="http://nelismithline.com">nelismithline.com</a>. But the other applications I run are only for my private use so I can just map them to another sub-domain such as <i>whatever.neilsmithline.com</i>. For example, I've been playing with a cloud-based bookmarking system, <a href="http://www.phoboslab.org/projects/asaph">Asaph</a>, that allows you to host the bookmarks. You can see it at <a href="http://www2.neilsmithline.com/asaph/">http://www2.neilsmithline.com/asaph/</a> if you have an interest in seeing the service in action.
</p>
<p>
All-in-all, it's like a nerd's dream come true :-D
</p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/02/01/nastiest_hack_ive_seen_in_awhile/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/02/01/nastiest_hack_ive_seen_in_awhile/index.html</guid>
<title>Nastiest Hack I've Seen In Awhile</title>
<dc:date>2012-02-01T20:40:51-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>coding</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<!-- NANOBLOGGER METADATA - END -->

<!-- The posting body follows this END_HTML directive -->

<p>
I was reading about <a href="http://code.google.com/p/android-scripting">SL4A</a>, also known as <a href="http://android.com">Android</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scripting_language">Scripting Languages</a>. They are a set of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quick_and_dirty">quick-and-dirty</a> ports of programming languages to the Android that interact with the Android <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_system">OS</a>. I just stumbled upon this "<a href="http://code.google.com/p/android-scripting/issues/detail?id=184">issue page</a>" (it's more like a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_forum">forum</a> than a bug report). 
</p>
<p>
The developer is trying to run something on his Android, which is basically <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux">Linux</a>, that requires <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Superuser">superuser</a> permissions. As the responses started to build upon each other, one user suggested starting his shell script with the following lines (the actual posting was in Android's flavor of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_(programming_language)">Python</a> but I've converted it to <a href="http://linux.die.net/man/1/su">bash(1)</a> to make it more accessible):
</p>



<pre class="example">#!/bin/sh
if [ "$USER" != "root" ]; then
    exec sudo $SHELL -c "`cat /proc/$$/cmdline | tr '\000' ' '`" root
fi
</pre>


<p>
I simply couldn't help being entertained at how revolting yet simply brilliant that code is. I hate when I run a command and it behaves stupidly because I didn't run it as the correct user. For example, this is the output of running <a href="http://linux.die.net/man/8/apt-get">apt-get(8)</a> without proper permission:
</p>



<pre class="example">$ apt-get install foobar
E: Could not open lock file /var/lib/dpkg/lock - open (13: Permission denied)
E: Unable to lock the administration directory (/var/lib/dpkg/), are you root?
</pre>


<p>
So I have to rerun the command with <a href="http://linux.die.net/man/8/sudo">sudo(8)</a>? I guess that makes sense in some situations but it grates on my nerves. Including the above lines in your shell scripts will automatically run commands as root when you need root privileges. It will also do this without bypassing the security of sudo. That is, if you don't have permission to run a command with sudo, then this won't help.
</p>
<p>
Despite the plain hackery of the above code, I expanded upon it, making it a full shell script utility. You can look the code or grab a copy at my <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a> <a href="https://github.com/Neil-Smithline">page</a> in the <a href="https://github.com/Neil-Smithline/rerunasroot">rerunasroot</a> repository.
</p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/01/14/man_vs_beast/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/01/14/man_vs_beast/index.html</guid>
<title>Man vs Beast</title>
<dc:date>2012-01-14T23:31:19-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[<!-- NANOBLOGGER METADATA - END -->

<!-- The posting body follows this END_HTML directive -->

<p>
I stumbled upon <a href="http://bit.ly/Ad2VZd">this article</a> in the Wikipedia about an annual 22-mile cross-country race where the participants are people running and people riding horses. After 25-years the first runner won the race. In the subsequent half-dozen years there have been several more human winners. 
</p>
<p>
I feel bad for any runner that is drafting a horse when the horse's tail goes up&hellip;
</p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/01/14/sopa_doa_not_quite_but_getting_there/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/01/14/sopa_doa_not_quite_but_getting_there/index.html</guid>
<title>SOPA DOA? Not Quite But Getting There</title>
<dc:date>2012-01-14T00:18:39-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>online-freedom</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<!-- NANOBLOGGER METADATA - END -->

<!-- The posting body follows this END_HTML directive -->
<p>
While not dead, SOPA is losing its teeth. Despite having had its major backer remove one of the more totalitarian portions from the bill (the ability to block non-US DNS addresses), SOPA appears unable to make progress in Congress. 
</p>
<p>
In a <a href="http://cnet.co/ArcHPH">CNET</a> article (via <a href="http://bit.ly/zMTg3h">Slashdot</a>), the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RIAA">RIAA</a> whines:
</p><blockquote>

<p>Instead of helping to come up with mechanisms to deny access to
the U.S. market by foreign criminals," the RIAA wrote, "the
opposition just keeps saying no. It is incumbent upon them to help
develop language that will ensure that criminals can't access our
market, while at the same time protecting our need for national
cybersecurity.
</p>
</blockquote>


<p>
As <a href="#SOPA-the-end-of-free-speech.org">discussed previously</a>, SOPA claims to support American businesses while it really supports the very large media companies and stifles smaller companies and individuals rights to publish.
</p>
<p>
As I've stated in my previous <a href="#SOPA-the-end-of-free-speech.org">posting about SOPA</a>, I am strongly opposed to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Piracy of software">piracy</a> as I am a software engineer (ie: software pays my rent). But I also believe that piracy can be dealt with without destroying <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_speech">free speech</a>. My viewpoints are similar to those of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_Frontier_Foundation">EFF</a> and differ from the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_Software_Foundation">FSF</a>'s viewpoint which opposes proprietary software altogether.
</p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/01/09/cool_animation/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/01/09/cool_animation/index.html</guid>
<title>Cool Animation</title>
<dc:date>2012-01-09T12:33:50-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>online-freedom</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<!-- NANOBLOGGER METADATA - END -->

<!-- The posting body follows this END_HTML directive -->

<p>
Google Plus Logo Animation by <a href="https://plus.google.com/115358085054420116311">ℑ. ℜ. Gellett</a>
<img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-POK887siH3w/Twq0UoK7YgI/AAAAAAAAAOg/dWGOAZzgcWQ/w300/Google-Plus-Logo-Animation-Small-JRGellett.GIF"  alt="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-POK887siH3w/Twq0UoK7YgI/AAAAAAAAAOg/dWGOAZzgcWQ/w300/Google-Plus-Logo-Animation-Small-JRGellett.GIF" />
</p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/01/05/stop_ptsd_support_the_wikipedia/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2012/01/05/stop_ptsd_support_the_wikipedia/index.html</guid>
<title>Stop PTSD, Support The Wikipedia</title>
<dc:date>2012-01-05T16:02:44-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>online-freedom</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<!-- NANOBLOGGER METADATA - END -->

<!-- The posting body follows this END_HTML directive -->


<em><p>
<p>
This posting is an updated version of my <a href="http://wikipedia.org/">Wikipedia</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User:Neil_Smithline">user page</a> originally posted on 6 Dec 2011.
<p/></em>

A few months ago I experienced what is known as a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Traumatic_event_(psychological)">traumatic event</a>.
</p>
<p>
It was a day like many other days. I was talking to my two sons and we had a disagreement about some fact. (I have no recollection what the fact being discussed was.) So, we did what we always do. We each reached for one of the nearby smartphones, tablets, netbooks, and laptops that populate our lives and went right to the <a href="http://wikipedia.org/">Wikipedia</a> to resolve the argument.
</p>
<p>
Then it happened. The Wikipedia was down. For a second or two, none of us knew what to do. Then we <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Googled">Googled</a> to find the answer to our question (I still can't remember the subject but I'm sure I was right :-).
</p>
<p>
But I started thinking, what would happen if the Wikipedia were to go away? It is not that I think the Wikipedia is perfect. In fact, I think it is chock full of problems. But, what makes the Wikipedia special is that the Wikipedia's problems are ours, the users', problems. They aren't owned by <a href="http://www.antipixel.com/blog/archives/2002/10/22/steal_these_buttons.html#000526">big government</a>, <a href="http://www.antipixel.com/blog/archives/2002/10/22/steal_these_buttons.html#000526">big business</a>, <a href="http://www.antipixel.com/blog/archives/2002/10/22/steal_these_buttons.html#000526">lobbyists</a>, the <a href="http://www.antipixel.com/blog/archives/2002/10/22/steal_these_buttons.html#000526">PRC</a>, or anyone else.
</p>
<p>
If there's a problem, you can edit the page and fix it. If you're uncertain what to do, you can add a comment about the problem on the discussion page with the hope that someone else will fix it or help you out.  Or you can simply ignore it. But, in all cases, <b>you</b> are making the decision.
</p>
<p>
So I donated $5 to the Wikipedia. That's about the same amount I tip the driver who delivers my groceries. 
</p>
<p>
Shortly after this traumatic event, the Wikipedia started posting these banner requests for donations. Personally, I find them increasingly annoying with every visit. But they are not nearly as annoying as the 10 minutes or so the Wikipedia was down. That downright spooked me.
</p>
<p>
Being they've continued to post the banner requests, I'm assuming they continue to need more money. So I decided to start what I'm calling The Wikipedia: Just Give campaign.
</p>
<p>
I'm not sure what the campaign will consist of, but I want to encourage everyone to give to the Wikipedia. I, who am totally untalented in the graphic arts, even made a few icons to help people join my campaign.
</p>
<p>
So I ask each of you to just give. If you don't have a lot, don't give a lot. But more importantly, encourage everyone you know to just give.
</p>
<p>
<b>Update 14 January 2012:</b> Just got this
</p><blockquote>

<p>  Sorry, the servers are overloaded at the moment.                            
</p>
<p>                                                                             
  Too many users are trying to view this page. Please wait a while before you access this page again.
</p>
<ul>
<li>Timeout waiting for the lock                                            
</li>
</ul>



</blockquote>




<p class="verse">
Neil Smithline, 6 December 2011<br/>
<i>A proud sponsor of the Wikipedia and its free information.</i><br/>
</p>



<div id="outline-container-1" class="outline-3">
<h3 id="sec-1">Resources</h3>
<div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1">

<p><i>Any artistic help on the badges would be deeply appreciated.</i>
</p>

</div>

<div id="outline-container-1-1" class="outline-4">
<h4 id="sec-1-1">HTML Code For Your Website</h4>
<div class="outline-text-4" id="text-1-1">

<p>Assuming I've gotten all my angle brackets matched and tags closed, depending on the system you use, you can add a graphic to your website or email signature by copy-and-pasting this:
</p>


<center>
<a 
  href="http://wikimediafoundation.org/w/index.php?title=WMFJA085/en/US" 
  target="_blank" title="Wikimedia donation page">
  <img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/34/Wikipedia_Just_Give-_Blue_Gray_Antipixel.png"
    alt="Blue and gray 'Just Give' icon"/>
</a>
<br/>
<span style="font-size: 75%;">
  (<a href="http://bit.ly/just-give" 
      target="_blank" 
      title="'Just Give' Campaign">what's this?</a>)
</span>
</center>

<p>
or this HTML:
</p>


<pre class="example">&lt;a 
  href="http://wikimediafoundation.org/w/index.php?title=WMFJA085/en/US" 
  target="_blank" title="Wikimedia donation page"&gt;
  &lt;img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/34/Wikipedia_Just_Give-_Blue_Gray_Antipixel.png"
    alt="Blue and gray 'Just Give' icon"/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 75%;"&gt;
  (&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/just-give" 
      target="_blank" 
      title="'Just Give' Campaign"&gt;what's this?&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/span&gt;
</pre>


</div>

</div>

<div id="outline-container-1-2" class="outline-4">
<h4 id="sec-1-2">Standard Badges (<a href="http://www.antipixel.com/blog/archives/2002/10/22/steal_these_buttons.html#000526">antipixel</a> style, 80x15px)</h4>
<div class="outline-text-4" id="text-1-2">


<br/><br/>
<table style='border: 2px solid black !important; border-collapse: separate;' cellspacing="0" cellpadding="6" rules="all" frame="2">
<caption></caption>
<colgroup><col class="left" /><col class="left" />
</colgroup>
<tbody>
<tr><td class="left">Blue and gray "Just Give"</td><td class="left"><img src="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wiki-just-give-blue-gray-antipixel.png"  alt="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wiki-just-give-blue-gray-antipixel.png" /></td></tr>
<tr><td class="left">Blue and white "Just Give"</td><td class="left"><img src="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wiki-just-give-blue-white-antipixel.png"  alt="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wiki-just-give-blue-white-antipixel.png" /></td></tr>
<tr><td class="left">Gray and blue "Just Give"</td><td class="left"><img src="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wiki-just-give-gray-blue-antipixel.png"  alt="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wiki-just-give-gray-blue-antipixel.png" /></td></tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</div>

</div>

<div id="outline-container-1-3" class="outline-4">
<h4 id="sec-1-3">Other Badges</h4>
<div class="outline-text-4" id="text-1-3">


<br/><br/>
<table style='border: 2px solid black !important; border-collapse: separate;' cellspacing="0" cellpadding="6" rules="all" frame="2">
<caption></caption>
<colgroup><col class="left" /><col class="left" />
</colgroup>
<tbody>
<tr><td class="left">Blue "Just Give", 172x66px</td><td class="left"><img src="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-172x66.png"  alt="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-172x66.png" /></td></tr>
<tr><td class="left">Yellow "Vote", 203x78px</td><td class="left"><img src="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-203x78.png"  alt="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-203x78.png" /></td></tr>
<tr><td class="left">Blue "Just Give, 229x88px</td><td class="left"><img src="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-229x88.png"  alt="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-229x88.png" /></td></tr>
<tr><td class="left">Blue "Just Give", 305x117px</td><td class="left"><img src="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-305x117.png"  alt="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-305x117.png" /></td></tr>
<tr><td class="left">Blue "Just Give, 406x156px</td><td class="left"><img src="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-406x156.png"  alt="http://neilsmithline.com/images/just-give/Wikipedia-just-give-406x156.png" /></td></tr>
</tbody>
</table>




<br/>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2011/12/30/florida_appeals_court_more_liberal_than_sopa/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2011/12/30/florida_appeals_court_more_liberal_than_sopa/index.html</guid>
<title>Florida Appeals Court More Liberal Than SOPA!</title>
<dc:date>2011-12-30T12:26:33-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>online-freedom</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<!-- NANOBLOGGER METADATA - END -->

<!-- The posting body follows this END_HTML directive -->

<p>
Earlier this week, the Florida appeals court made a ruling that even the poster of a defamatory posting on a public website could not force a website to remove the posting. While most sites allow you to remove your own postings, <a href="http://www.ripoffreport.com/">RipoffReport.com</a>, the site involved in this ruling, states that as an advocate of free speech, it never removes reports. This is clearly stated at the top of their home page and documented extensively on their <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ripoff_Report#Non-removal_Policy">Wikipedia page</a>. 
</p>
<p>
While not allowing the poster to remove or have removed a posting seems extreme, the site claims that it wishes to remain unbiased. As such, it makes no judgment calls about its content. Everything that is appropriate for the site will stay on the site, forever. RipoffReport.com is afraid that posters may be pressured by 3<sup>rd</sup>-parties to remove articles. As such, They are simply not allowed to.
</p>
<p>
While postings are never removed, the site allows anyone to post a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rebuttal">rebuttal</a> to any posting. A poster can use this mechanism to retract their initial statement. 
</p>
<p>
The court ruled that RipoffReport.com could neither be held liable for the defamatory posting nor be forced to remove it. The bottom line of all of this is that
</p>

<div style="text-align: center">
<p>The supreme court of Florida, a <a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/125066/State-States.aspx">middle-of-the-road state</a>, was willing to make a controversial ruling favored many aspects of freedom of speech. If SOPA is passed, cases like this won't even make it to courts as SOPA make it clear that if a ruling is defamatory, it is illegal.
</p>
</div>

<p>
While Congress has delayed voting on SOPA for another month, it is still on the docket. It is unclear what the fate of SOPA will be. 
</p>
<p>
One can hope that Congress pays attention to protests such as the statement]] consumers sent to <a href="http://www.godaddy.com">GoDaddy</a> after it announced its support of SOPA. GoDaddy announced that on a Saturday (see <a href="http://news.slashdot.org/story/11/12/29/2053252/wikipedia-to-dump-godaddy-over-sopa">more complete chronology</a>) and then lost <a href="http://tech.slashdot.org/story/11/12/25/1452251/go-daddy-loses-over-21000-domains-in-one-daylosing">21K domains</a> on the next day. More recently, the <a href="http://news.slashdot.org/story/11/12/29/2053252/wikipedia-to-dump-godaddy-over-sopa">Wikipedia announced it would discontinue all use of GoDaddy</a>. 
</p>
<p>
Let's continue to hope that advocates of free speech, including you (see <a href="SOPA-the-end-of-free-speech.html#ID-06BB29E4-D6B3-430E-B5A3-FDC6716A0ED3">SOPA: The End Of Free Speech</a> for instructions as to how to help), continue to pressure our government into sane activit
</p>
<p>
Copied directly from the <a href="http://www.slashdot.org">Slashdot</a> <a href="http://bit.ly/vVVDLC">article</a>:
</p><blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.ripoffreport.com/">RipoffReport.com</a> contained an admittedly defamatory posting, by one of its users, about a person who operated a Florida corporation providing addiction treatment services. Although the site was asked by the poster herself to remove the post, it refused. A Florida appeals court has ruled that the site is absolutely immune from suit (<a href="http://recordingindustryvspeople.blogspot.com/2011/12/florida-appeals-court-rules.html">pdf</a>), and cannot even be directed to remove the offending post, since under the [[http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/html/uscode47/usc<sub>sec</sub><sub>47</sub><sub>00000230</sub>-&mdash;000-.html][Communications Decency Act (47 USC 230)] 'no cause of action may be brought' against a provider of an "interactive computer service" based upon information provided by a 3rd party.
</p>
</blockquote>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2011/12/28/the_litigious_trio/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2011/12/28/the_litigious_trio/index.html</guid>
<title>The Litigious Trio</title>
<dc:date>2011-12-28T12:04:20-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>online-freedom, litigious-trio</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<!-- NANOBLOGGER METADATA - END -->

<!-- The posting body follows this END_HTML directive -->

<p>
This posting is best viewed as part of the series of postings about <a href="http://neilsmithline.com/archives/litigious-trio/index.html">The Litigious Trio</a> and, in a larger context, <a href="http://neilsmithline.com/archives/online-freedom/index.html">Online Freedom</a>.
</p>
<p>
To be clear, <i>The Litigious Trio</i> are, in alphabetical order, <a href="http://apple.com">Apple</a>, <a href="http://google.com">Google</a> and <a href="http://microsoft.com">Microsoft</a>. While they are three wonderful technology companies, over time, each has turned to an increasingly large amount of litigation to enforce their current market status.
</p>
<p>
While I do not believe that the three companies actively collaborate with each other to hinder the success of smaller companies, I believe that selfish<sup><a class="footref" name="fnr.1" href="#fn.1">1</a></sup> business practices by the trio have had the affect of having created a three company monopoly<sup><a class="footref" name="fnr.2" href="#fn.2">2</a></sup>. While the three companies are locked in a near-endless stream of litigation against each other, this is rather typical amongst large corporate competitors. I can't say that I'm in favor of such litigation but I the three companies can spend their money that way if they want to. They have more than enough of it.
</p>
<p>
But when <i>The Litigious Trio</i>, behaving in a pseudo-monopolistic manner, use litigation to block competition from smaller companies, they end up stifling innovation. 
</p>
<p>
Furthermore, <i>The Litigious Trio</i> are not necessarily the most user-friendly companies. They, along with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook">Facebook</a>, are some of the leaders in gathering information about its users. Consider the following:
</p><ul>
<li>Nearly all of Google's revenue comes from advertising. Their advertising is so valuable, and profitable, because they are able to sell well targeted ads. That is, they know so much about each user that they can sell ad space for that specific user for more than other advertising vendors. The article, <a href="http://www.globalreports.com/?article=12">We Are Google's Products</a>, provides a good summary of this concept. 
</li>
<li>Google has a near-monopoly on internet advertising. The US Senate <a href="http://tech.slashdot.org/story/11/12/21/1356246/senators-recommend-ftc-perform-antitrust-investigation-of-google">has recently requested</a> the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Federal_Trade_Commission">FTC</a> to investigate this.
</li>
<li>Microsoft's <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=microsoft+antitrust&amp;ie=utf-8&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;aq=t&amp;rls=org.mozilla:en-US:unofficial&amp;client=firefox-a">monopolistic practices</a> have been discussed and challenged by courts around the world for years.
</li>
<li>Apple is currently under investigation for <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/12/07/us-justice-department-apple-ebooks_n_1134983.html">price fixing on its eBooks</a>, has just been fined for <a href="http://www.pluggedin.co.uk/article/apple-fined-over-misleading-customers-italy">charging customers in Italy</a> for providing federally mandated, free support, and has tried to <a href="http://apple.slashdot.org/story/11/08/09/1832254/sale-of-samsung-galaxy-tab-blocked-in-the-eu">destroy Samsung's mobile market</a> by presenting <a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/story/11/08/15/1758224/flawed-evidence-in-eu-apple-vs-samsung-case">falsified evidence</a> to courts around the world. While this last claim seems hard to believe, an <a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/238047/apple_offers_flawed_evidence_in_lawsuit_against_samsung.html">easily accessible description and images</a> demonstrate that Apple is either incompetent or dishonest.
</li>
</ul>



<p>
The only question seems to be whether the public is motivated to address this problem and what the public can do to address it. The reason monopolies are illegal is because fighting them is difficult.
</p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2011/12/20/unix_reference_add_user_to_a_group/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2011/12/20/unix_reference_add_user_to_a_group/index.html</guid>
<title>Unix Reference: Add User To A Group</title>
<dc:date>2011-12-20T08:25:20-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>reference, unix-reference</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[

<p>
<a href="http://linux.die.net/man/8/usermod">usermod</a> -a -G GID1,GID2,&hellip;GIDn USERNAME
</p>
<ul>
<li>
USERNAME must already exist
</li>
<li>
The one or more GIDs must already exist
</li>
<li>
Omitting the <i>-a</i> will first remove the user from all groups except their login group and then add them to groups GIDs.





<!-- For GNU Emacs
--
-- Local Variables:
-- org-export-nb-id:      "2011-12-20T08_25_20"
-- org-export-nb-tags:  "unix-reference,reference"
-- End: 
--
------------------------------------------------
--
-- LocalWords: nb
-->]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2011/12/15/sparkleshare_maybe_an_open_privately_hosted_dropbox_alternative/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.neilsmithline.com/feed/archives/2011/12/15/sparkleshare_maybe_an_open_privately_hosted_dropbox_alternative/index.html</guid>
<title>Sparkleshare: Maybe An Open, Privately Hosted, Dropbox Alternative</title>
<dc:date>2011-12-15T01:49:25-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Smithline</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>sync-software, software</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[

<p> 
<a href="http://dropbox.com">Dropbox</a> took the internet by storm with its free storage and ease of
access. But Dropbox comes with a limited amount of data, a level of
secureness that is hard-to-understand, and rather proprietary.
</p>
<p>
<a href="http://sparkleshare.org">Sparkleshare</a> is an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_Open_Source_Software">open source</a> alternative to Dropbox that hit my
radar screen about 6 months ago. I played with it a bit back then but
it didn't seem to be quite there. I think I was using an early-alpha,
pre-release version so I this was to be expected.
</p>
<p>
I gave it another try earlier this week and seem to be pretty happy
with it. Some of the things I like about it include:
</p><ol>
<li>I get to host it on my own server. This means the data is
     private. I own it. Nobody else has a copy of it. Etc&hellip;
</li>
<li>I have been renting a Linux <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_server">VPS</a> from <a href="http://rosehosting.com">RoseHosting.com</a> ($20/month)
     for many years so they provide me with a convenient, managed, and
     relatively secure place to host Sparkleshare.
</li>
<li>It only took me about 5 minutes to install and configure
     sparkleshare on my Linux VPS. Not because I'm brilliant but
     because Linux doesn't suck and Sparkleshare requires no special
     server software. Just a few standard packages such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Git_(software)">Git</a> and a
     copy-and-paste of one command line. The client install (Mac OS X)
     was equally simple.
</li>
<li>Being that it is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_Open_Source_Software">FOSS</a>, there is continual scrutiny of the source
     code to maintain quality and security.
</li>
</ol>


<p>
The only real objection I have with it is that Dropbox allows <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Symbolic_link">symbolic links</a> in the Dropbox folder so I don't need to have all of my files in
one directory. I haven't yet gotten this to work on Sparkleshare.
Either I just haven't figured it out, someone else will add it
shortly, or, being it is <a href="http://www.wikipedia.com/Foss">FOSS</a>, I'll add it if I get motivated enough
(BTW: I'm voting for someone else implementing it).
</p>



<!-- For GNU Emacs
--
-- Local Variables:
-- org-export-nb-id:    "2011-12-15T01_49_25"
-- org-export-nb-tags:  "sync-software,software"
-- End: 
--
------------------------------------------------
--
-- LocalWords: nb
-->]]>
</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
